A Guide to the Papers of The Colson-Hill Family
Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
- Organizations and Affiliations of Edna MEade Colson Edna Meade Colson
  - Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority
    - History-Delta Omega Chapter (Box-folder 57:1)
    - Correspondence 1929-1959 (Box-folder 57:2)
    - Correspondence 1971-1974 (Box-folder 57:4)
    - Correspondence 1974-1977 (Box-folder 57:5)
    - Chapter Directory 1969 (Box-folder 57:6)
    - Meeting Agenda 1969-1972 (Box-folder 57:7)
    - Obituaries (AKA's) (Box-folder 57:8)
    - Biography- Soror Felicia Anderson (Box-folder 57:9)
    - Biography-Anna Laura Lindsay (Box-folder 57:10)
    - Conveyance-Mary E.Branch Portrait (Box-folder 57:11)
    - AKA-Programs 1925,1927,1970-1971 (Box-folder 57:12)
    - AKA-Report of Audit Committee 1969,1973 (Box-folder 57:14)
    - AKA-Committee in Awards 1961 (Box-folder 57:15)
    - AKA-Newsletters 1953-1973 (Box-folder 57:16)
    - AKA-Certificates 1976 (Box-folder 57:17)
    - AKA-Newsletter 1973-1976 (Box-folder 57:18)
    - AKA-Program Forty-Seventh Boule 1976 (Box-folder 57a)
    - AKA-Printed History of the South Atlantic Region (Othertype 57b)
    - Constitution and By Laws 1974 (Othertype 57b)
    - Manual of Standard Procedures 1973 (Othertype 57b)
    - Yearbook for AKA 1974-1977,1982 (Othertype 57b)
    - Founders Day Invitation 1950,1964,1973,1974-1975 (Othertype 57b)
    - Membership Card (Othertype 57b)
  - The Red Cross (Chesterfield Co. Va Chapter, The Colored Auxiliary)
    - Red Cross- By Laws- Membership (Box-folder 58:1)
    - Red Cross- Minutes 1947 (Box-folder 58:2)
    - Red Cross- Minutes 1948 (Box-folder 58:3)
    - Red Cross Correspondence 1929-1933 (Box-folder 58:4)
    - Red Cross Correspondence 1934-1942 (Box-folder 58:5)
    - Red Cross Correspondence Feb 1943-Mar 1943 (Box-folder 58:6)
    - Red Cross Correspondence Apr 1943-Dec 1943 (Box-folder 58:7)
    - Red Cross Correspondence 1944-1946 (Box-folder 58:8)
    - Red Cross Correspondence 1947 (Box-folder 58:9)
    - Red Cross Correspondence 1948-1959 (Box-folder 58:10)
    - Red Cross Printed Item (Box-folder 58:11)
    - Red Cross Printed Items (Box-folder 58:12)
  - The Virginia Society for Research
    - VA Society-Constitution (Box-folder 58:13)
    - VA Society-Correspondence 1930-1934 (Box-folder 58:14)
    - Va Society- Negro Education 1933 (Box-folder 58:15)
    - VA Society- Correspondence 1930-1934 (Box-folder 58:16)
    - VA Society Survey 1934 (Box-folder 58:17)
    - VA Society- Research Survey 1925 (Box-folder 58:18)
    - VA Society- Program 1935,1941 (Box-folder 58:19)
    - VA Society- Extracurricular Activities (Box-folder 58:20)
  - The Negro Organizational Society
    - Resolutions and Certificate of Incorporation 1920,1956 (Box-folder 59:1)
    - Correspondence 1912-1944 (Box-folder 59:2)
    - Correspondence 1950-1957 (Box-folder 59:3)
    - NOS- Printed (Programs) 1915 (Box-folder 59:4)
      - Petersburg,VA ( V N and I I) 1915
      - Lychburg, VA 1915
      - Newport News, VA 1920
      - Farmvile, VA 1932
      - Caroline County,VA 1936
    - NOS Printed (Programs) (Box-folder 59:5)
      - Rustburg, Campbell County, VA 1953
      - Carver 1956
      - Pamphlet 1920
      - Official Bulletin 1956
    - NOS Printed- The Progress Record (Box-folder 59:6)
      - The Progress Record April-June 1940
      - The Progress Report Oct-Dec 1942
      - The Progress Report April-June 1944
      - The Progress Report May 1947
      - The Progress Report Oct 1952
      - Newsletter 1946
  - Gillfield Babtist Church
    - Gillfield- General Correspondence 1969-1974 (Box-folder 59:7)
    - Gillfeild- Parrish Correspondence 1972-1974 (Box-folder 59:8)
    - Gillfield- Parrish Minutes 1973-1975 (Box-folder 59:9)
    - Gillfield-The Golden Age Club 1967-1974 (Box-folder 59:10)
    - Gillfield-Reports to Minister 1962,1975 (Box-folder 59:11)
    - Gillfield- Biographical Sketches for Gillfield (Box-folder 59:12)
    - Gillfield- Biographical Sketches for Gillfield (Box-folder 59:13)
    - Gillfield- Printed Items 1910,1974 (Box-folder 59:14)
  - The Links Inc.
    - The Links- Programs, Drawings 1946,1965 (Box-folder 59:15)
  - The Virginia Council On Interracial Relations
    - Interracial Group- Correspondence 1943 (Box-folder 59:16)
  - The Committee for Virginia
    - The Committee For Virginia Correspondence 1940,1946 (Box-folder 59:17)
  - The N.A.A.C.P.
    - N.A.A.C.P- Correspondence 1949,1953-1954 (Box-folder 59:18)
    - N.A.A.C.P- Petesburg Newsletter (Box-folder 59:19)
  - The Virginia Council On Human Relations
    - The V C H R- Correspondence, Newsletter 1955-1959 (Box-folder 60:1)
    - The V C H R- Correspondence, Newsletter Jan-Jul 1960 (Box-folder 60:2)
    - The V C H R- Correspondence, Newsletter Aug-Dec 1960 (Box-folder 60:3)
    - The V C H R- Correspondence, Newsletter 1961-1962 (Box-folder 60:4)
    - The V C H R- Correspondence, Newsletter Jun-Dec 1962 (Box-folder 60:5)
    - The V C H R- Correspondence, Newsletter 1963-1964 (Box-folder 60:6)
    - The V C H R- Correspondence, Newsletter 1966-1975 (Box-folder 60:7)
    - The V C H R- Reports, Memorandum 1967-1968 (Box-folder 60:8)
    - The V C H R- Reports, Memorandum (Box-folder 60:9)
    - The V C H R- Report 1966 (Box-folder 60:10)
    - The V C H R- Report (Box-folder 60:11)
    - The V C H R- Minutes 1963 (Box-folder 60:12)
    - The V C H R- Newsletters 1966-1968 (Box-folder 60:13)
    - The V C H R-Newsletters 1970-1971 (Box-folder 60:14)
    - The V C H R- Newsletter- Petersburg 1970 (Box-folder 60:15)
    - The V C H R- News-clippings (Box-folder 60:16)
  - Student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee
    - SNCC- History, Newsletters Printed, The Student View (Box-folder 60:17)
  - Th Southern Christian Leadership Conference
    - SCLC- Printed Newsletter (Box-folder 60:18)
- Literary,Diaries, Autograph Books, notebooks, speeches and writings
  - Diaries (Folio 61a)
    Four diaries maintained by James Major Colson Jr. beginning in January of 1878 and continuing through 1899. Not only did James Major Colson maintain a diary, his wife Kate also began in 1887 her first diray. Mrs. Colson's diary,however, only covers a few months of that year. Also, In this sub-series is a diary belonging to William Nelson Colson II, son of James and Kate Colson. The Diary begins in the summer of 1914 and continues to February 1915. During this time Mr.Colson was a member of the faculty at Virginia Union University in Richmond, VA.
  - Autographs, Books, Notebooks, Travel log (Folio 61a)
    Notebooks kept by James Major Colson and Kate Hill as students. Mr.Colson's notebook covers a variety of subjects taken taken at Dartmouth. Included is a notebook maintained for his class in Physics (1881-1882) other subjects include language, natural history, physiology, and literature. Mrs. Colson notebook covers a number of subjects, which would have been included in the study for a teaching certificate at this time.
  - Notebooks (Folio 61a)
    A Composition notebook kept by Edna M. Colson. The notebook appears to have been used to teach Sunday School classes. Two autograph books, one belonging to Miss Kate Hill (later Kate Colson) and dates from 1882-through Aug 1883. The other autograph book belongs to Miss Edna Meade Colson and covers the time span from 1907 through 1909. There is also a travel log which was kept by Edna M. Colson, no date.
  - Writings and Speeches
    - "The Jolly Boys"- A Poem 1881 James Major Colson 1871 (Box-folder 62:1)
    - Paper read before Delta Kappa- J.M.C. 1879 (Box-folder 62:2)
    - A Biography (Box-folder 62:3)
    - "The Death of My Son" Fannie Meade Colson 1909 (Box-folder 62:4)
    - "State Board of Accreditation" E.M.C 1912 (Box-folder 62:5)
    - "Commencement Essay" E.M.C 1915 (Box-folder 62:6)
    - "Unsolved Problem:Should Slavery be culminated in American History" E.M.C 1924 (Box-folder 62:7)
    - "Objectives of Mental Training" E.M.C 1924 (Box-folder 62:8)
    - "To The Editor of the Weekly Reader" 1924 (Box-folder 62:9)
    - "Some Findings of Value to the Negro College" E.M.C. 1927 (Box-folder 62:10)
    - "Outcome of a Research Undertaking" E.M.C. 1930 (Box-folder 62:11)
    - "Regarding a philosophy of life and education" E.M.C 1931 (Box-folder 62:12)
    - The Function and place of the export graph project Edna Meade Colson, Felton Clark, Robert H. Morrison, Ben Heflin and Verna A. Carley (Box-folder 62:13)
    - Stereotypes in Human Relations E.M.C (Box-folder 62:14)
    - Principles Governing the work of the Teacher College Writings- E.M.C. Writings Myra Colson Calls (Box-folder 62:15)
    - The Employment Process of Negro women in The United States- Writings- J.M.C IV 1890-1920 (Box-folder 62:16)
    - Square Goodwyns Farm 11/12/1912 (Box-folder 62:17)
    - Autobiographies 5/2/1913 (Box-folder 62:17)
    - Edna Meade Colson- untitled (Box-folder 62:17)
    - Unsolved Problem in Negro Education 1920 (Box-folder 62:18)
    - Commencement 1925 (Box-folder 62:19)
    - Some Economic Opportunities of The Colored College Women 1937 (Box-folder 62:20)
    - The Spirit of VIrginia State College (Box-folder 62:21)
    - The Effects of The Present Emerging Upon the Negro Family (Box-folder 62:22)
    - There was a Woman (Box-folder 62:23)
    - Friendship (Box-folder 62:24)
    - The Place of Religion In Our Demcracy (Box-folder 62:25)
    - Recent Curriculum Revision at Virginia State College (Box-folder 62:26)
    - Women, Education, adn Democracy (Box-folder 62:27)
    - Women's Work In a changing world (Box-folder 62:28)
    - The Education or Growth of the child through study (Box-folder 62:29)
    - The Ideal V N and II Girl (Box-folder 62:30)
    - Who shall we teach and why? (Box-folder 62:31)
    - Remarks to those Present at the Commencement (Box-folder 62:32)
    - The Negro Woman as a breadwinner (Box-folder 62:33)
    - The Place of the Expert in Modern Life (Box-folder 62:34)
    - The Retirement of James Hugo Johnston (Box-folder 62:35)
    - French Schools (Box-folder 62:36)
    - French Schools (Box-folder 62:36)
    - Strengthening The Teaching Professions (Box-folder 62:37)
    - Unsolved Problems in Negro Education (Box-folder 62:38)
    - The College Grad faces life (Box-folder 63:1)
    - A Plea for Individuality (Box-folder 63:2)
    - Present Day Theory Applied to Elementary Education (Box-folder 63:3)
    - Unanswered Questions (Box-folder 63:4)
    - The Negro Child and the Curriculum (Box-folder 63:5)
    - Freedom and Morality (Box-folder 63:6)
    - The Negro Woman as Breadwinner (Box-folder 63:7)
    - The College Graduate looks at life (Box-folder 63:8)
    - What are the Common Educational Problems confronting the races in Virginia (Box-folder 63:9)
    - The History of the class of 1915 (Box-folder 63:10)
    - No Title (Box-folder 63:11)
    - No Title (Box-folder 63:12)
    - No Title (Box-folder 63:13)
    - No Title (Box-folder 63:14)
    - No Title (Box-folder 63:15)
    - No Title (Box-folder 63:16)
    - No Title (Box-folder 63:17)
    - No Title (Box-folder 63:18)
    - No Title (Box-folder 63:19)
    - No Title (Box-folder 63:20)
    - No Title (Box-folder 63:21)
    - No Title (Box-folder 63:22)
    - No Title (Box-folder 63:23)
    - No Title (Box-folder 63:24)
    - No Title (Box-folder 63:25)
    - No Title (Box-folder 63:26)
    - The Destiny of the Negro (JMC III) (Box-folder 63:27)
    - Citizen Soldier (JMC III) (Box-folder 63:28)
    - No Title (JMC III) (Box-folder 63:29)
- Financial
  - Receipts, Bills, and School grades
    - Business Bills and Receipts Rent (Copy) 1836 (Box-folder 64:1)
    - School- J.M.C. 1883 (Box-folder 64:2)
    - Medical 1892-1910 (Box-folder 64:3)
    - Medical (Box-folder 64:4)
    - Burial James M. Colson 1909 (Box-folder 64:5)
    - Rosenstock and Co. Clothing 1886-1911 (Box-folder 64:6)
    - Rosenstock and Co. Clothing 1912-1917 (Box-folder 64:7)
    - Clothing (non-Rosenstock) 1909-1914 (Box-folder 64:8)
    - Clothing (non-Rosenstock) 1911-1915 (Box-folder 64:9)
    - Furniture 1910-1914 (Box-folder 64:10)
    - General Receipts 1884,1892-1915 (Box-folder 64:11)
    - General Receipts 1909-1914 (Box-folder 64:12)
    - General Receipts 1913-1915 (Box-folder 64:13)
    - General Receipts Food 1910-1916 (Box-folder 64:14)
    - General Receipts Groceries 1911-1914 (Box-folder 64:15)
    - Receipts (General Contractor) 1908-1920 (Box-folder 64:16)
    - Receipts (General Contractor) 1921 (Box-folder 64:17)
    - Building on Sycamore 1917 (Box-folder 64:18)
    - Building on Sycamore 1917 (Box-folder 64:19)
    - Receipts- Rental Egerton Co. 1907-1908 (Box-folder 65:1)
    - Receipts- Rental Egerton Co. 1909-1910 (Box-folder 65:2)
    - Receipts- Rental Egerton Co. 1911-1913 (Box-folder 65:3)
    - Receipts- Rental Egerton Co. 1914-1916 (Box-folder 65:4)
    - Receipts- Rental Egerton Co. 1917-1919 (Box-folder 65:5)
    - Receipts- Rental Egerton Co. 1920-1921 (Box-folder 65:6)
    - Receipts- Rental Hall Co. 1912-1913 (Box-folder 65:7)
    - Receipts- Rental Hall Co. 1920-1923 (Box-folder 65:8)
    - Receipts- Rental Hall Co. 1924 (Box-folder 65:9)
    - Receipts- Rental Hall Co. 1924 (Box-folder 65:9)
    - Receipts- Moyler and Lyon 1920-1923 (Box-folder 65:10)
    - Receipts- Moyler and Lyon 1922-1926 (Box-folder 65:11)
    - Receipts- Rental Books and Richardson 1927 (Box-folder 65:12)
    - Receipts-Rental Books and Richardson 1928 (Box-folder 65:13)
    - Receipts- Rental Goodwyn 1925 (Box-folder 65:14)
    - Receipts- Rental Harrison and Dyer (Box-folder 65:15)
    - Receipts- Rental General (Box-folder 65:16)
    - List of Red Estate 1884-1886 (Box-folder 65:17)
    - From Account Book 1887,1927 (Box-folder 65:18)
  - Financial Documents
    - Cancelled Checks (Box-folder 65:19)
    - Bank Drafts (Box-folder 65:20)
  - Insurance
    - Insurance Policies (Box-folder 65:21)
  - Ledgers and Bank Books
    - Estate Record Book 1888 (Othertype 66)
    - Expense Book 1909-1917 (Othertype 66)
    - Rent Book (Othertype 66)
    - Expense Book 1908 (Othertype 66)
    - Monthly time book 1915 (Othertype 66)
    - Petersburg Savings and In. Co. 1912-1914 (Othertype 66)
    - The National Bank 1884-1901 (Othertype 66)
- Photographs
  - Family
    - Bragg- Children (Box-folder 67:1)
    - Bragg-Children and Others (Box-folder 67:2)
    - Bragg- Mary, Nelle and Myra Colson (Box-folder 67:3)
    - Bragg- George F. (Box-folder 67:4)
    - Callis Henry (Box-folder 67:5)
    - Callis, Henry (Box-folder 67:6)
    - Cheyney, Myra Colson 1908-1911 (Box-folder 67:7)
    - Cheyney, Myra Colson 1908-1911 (Box-folder 67:8)
    - Callis (Colson), Myra at Petersburg 1917-1919 (Box-folder 67:9)
    - Callis (Colson), Myra at Winston-Salem 1924 (Box-folder 67:10)
    - Students at Hartshorn (Box-folder 67:11)
    - Myra Photo's and postcards (Box-folder 67:12)
    - Mrs. H. Callis (Box-folder 67:13)
    - Callis (Colson), Myra at Cheyney (Box-folder 67:14)
    - Callis (Colson) Myra Niagara Fl. (Box-folder 67:15)
    - Hartshorn College for Women- Va. Union (Box-folder 67:16)
    - Richmond (Unidentified Females) School Scenes (Box-folder 67:17)
    - Callis, Myra YMCA (Box-folder 67:18)
    - Callis, Myra Family (Colson) (Box-folder 67:19)
    - Colson, Adele (Box-folder 67:20)
    - Colson, Corlandt (Box-folder 67:21)
    - Colson, Cortlandt 1955 (Box-folder 67:22)
    - Cortlandt and Myra Colson (Box-folder 67:23)
    - Colson, Dorothy (Box-folder 67:24)
    - Colson, Edna Meade (Box-folder 67:25)
    - Colson, Edna Meade (Box-folder 67:26)
    - Colson, Edna Meade (Box-folder 67:27)
    - Colson, Edna Meade (Box-folder 67:28)
    - Colson, Edna Meade (Box-folder 67:29)
    - Memories- Fall- Edna and Myra Colson 1915 (Box-folder 67:30)
    - Colson, Edna Meade (Box-folder 67:31)
    - Colson, Edna Meade (Box-folder 67:32)
    - Colson, Edna Meade (Box-folder 67:33)
    - Edna Colson 1950's (Box-folder 67:34)
    - James Major Colson II, Fannie Meade Bolling Wedding Photo (Box-folder 67:35)
    - Colson, James M. III (Box-folder 67:36)
    - Colson, James M. Jr. 1854-1904 (Box-folder 67:37)
    - Colson, James M. III 1854-1904 (Box-folder 67:38)
    - Coslon, James M. 1854-1904 (Box-folder 67:39)
    - Mrs. H. Callis (Box-folder 67:40)
    - Colson, Edna -group (Box-folder 67:41)
    - V.S.U Administrators 1953 (Box-folder 67:42)
    - Colson, Edna and group (Box-folder 67:43)
    - Coslon, Edna and William (Box-folder 67:44)
    - Edna Colson Photos (Box-folder 67:45)
    - Edna Meade Colson (Box-folder 67:46)
    - Edna Meade Colson (Bolling) (Box-folder 67:47)
    - Colson, Henry (Box-folder 67:48)
    - Colson Family (Box-folder 67:49)
    - Diane- 1942 (Box-folder 67:50)
    - Colson, Myra (Box-folder 67:51)
    - Colson, Myra 1955 (Box-folder 67:52)
    - Colson, Cortlandt 1955 (Box-folder 67:53)
    - Colson, Edna Meade (Box-folder 67:54)
    - Colson, Edna Meade (Box-folder 67:55)
    - James Major Colson III and Family (Box-folder 67:56)
    - Colson, James M III (Box-folder 67:57)
    - James Major Colson III (gravesite) (Box-folder 67:58)
    - Baker, Jean (Colson) (Box-folder 67:59)
    - James Major Colson III (youngster) (Box-folder 68:1)
    - Wiley Hall- Virginia Union- James M. Colson IV (Box-folder 68:2)
    - Colson, James IV (Box-folder 68:3)
    - Colson, James Major IV (Box-folder 68:4)
    - Mr. and Mrs. James Major Colson IV (Box-folder 68:5)
    - Colson IV- Miscellaneous (Box-folder 68:6)
    - James Major Colson (Box-folder 68:7)
    - Kate Hill (Box-folder 68:8)
    - Colson, Kate and Cortlandt (Box-folder 68:9)
    - Colson, Kate (Box-folder 68:10)
    - Colson, Kate (Box-folder 68:11)
    - Colson, Kate (Box-folder 68:12)
    - Kate and Adele, Kate Colson (Box-folder 68:13)
    - Kate (Hill) Colson (Box-folder 68:14)
    - Kate (Hill) Colson (Box-folder 68:15)
    - Kate (Hill) Colson (Box-folder 68:16)
    - Kate Colson and Anna L. Lindsay (Box-folder 68:17)
    - William N. Colson II (Box-folder 68:18)
    - Hattie Freeman (Colson) (Box-folder 68:19)
    - Charles Freeman (Box-folder 68:20)
    - Nannie Hampton (Hill) (Box-folder 68:21)
    - Sue Hampton (Hill) (Box-folder 68:22)
    - John Harris (Box-folder 68:23)
    - John Henry Hill (Box-folder 68:24)
    - John Henry Hill (Box-folder 68:25)
    - John Henry Hill and Rosetta (McCray) Hill (Box-folder 68:26)
    - Rosetta (McCray) Hill (Box-folder 68:27)
    - H.C. Jackson and Dorothy (Box-folder 68:28)
    - Mrs. Melvin West (Colson) (Box-folder 68:29)
    - Mary (Colson) Woody and David (Box-folder 68:30)
    - Family Home Exterior (Box-folder 68:31)
    - Family Home Interior (Box-folder 68:32)
    - Building Interior (Box-folder 68:33)
  - John A. Dix Industrial School
    - The John A. Dix School (Classroom) (Box-folder 68:34)
    - The John. A Dix School (baseball) (Box-folder 68:35)
    - John Nelson Scott (Box-folder 68:36)
    - The John A. Dix School (Student) (Box-folder 68:37)
    - The John A. Dix School (Students) (Box-folder 68:38)
    - The John A. Dix School (Students) (Box-folder 68:39)
    - The John A. Dix School (Students) (Box-folder 68:40)
    - The John A. Dix School (Building) (Box-folder 68:41)
    - The John A. Dix School (Cadet Camp) (Box-folder 68:42)
    - The John A. Dix School (Faculty and Students) (Box-folder 68:43)
    - Alpha Kappa Alpha- Edna Colson (Box-folder 68:44)
    - Classroom Scene 1950's (Box-folder 68:45)
    - Founder's Day 1963 (Box-folder 68:46)
    - Negatives (Box-folder 68:47)
    - Landscapes (Box-folder 68:48)
    - Gayle Marie Colson (Frame 69)
    - Edna Colson (Frame 69)
    - Myra Colson (Frame 69)
  - William Nelson Colson
    - Lt. William Nelson Colson (Frame 69)
    - 4 Unidentified Photographs (Frame 69)
    - Lt. William Nelson Colson (Box-folder 70:1)
    - Lt. William Nelson Colson (Box-folder 70:2)
    - Thomas, Colson, Ware (Box-folder 70:3)
    - Prepare for Birovac (Box-folder 70:4)
    - Hospital Corps (Box-folder 70:5)
    - Kneeling (Box-folder 70:6)
    - Miss Time (Box-folder 70:7)
    - The Prone Position (Box-folder 70:8)
    - Rest (Box-folder 70:9)
    - Retreat (Box-folder 70:10)
    - Route Step (Box-folder 70:11)
    - Sketching Class (Box-folder 70:12)
    - Target Range (Box-folder 70:13)
    - Trenching (Box-folder 70:14)
    - Colson Balbu (Box-folder 70:15)
    - Sgt. Bruggs (Box-folder 70:16)
    - Col. Cooks, Sgt. Wynn (Box-folder 70:17)
    - Dale, Evans, and Guppy (Box-folder 70:18)
    - Sgt. Earl (Box-folder 70:19)
    - Ex. Capt. Frierson (Box-folder 70:20)
    - Gibbs (Box-folder 70:21)
    - The Gould Brothers (Box-folder 70:22)
    - Harvey (Box-folder 70:23)
    - Harry (Box-folder 70:24)
    - Krigger (Box-folder 70:25)
    - Lewis, Ponter, and Woof (Box-folder 70:26)
    - Wright and Rivers (Box-folder 70:27)
    - Sergeant Simmons (Box-folder 70:28)
    - Col. Sturtevants Home (Box-folder 70:29)
    - J.E. Scott (Box-folder 70:30)
    - Alpha Phi Alpha- ROTC (Box-folder 70:31)
    - Company 1 (Box-folder 70:32)
    - 3rd Provisional Company (Box-folder 70:33)
    - Harvard Men (Box-folder 70:34)
    - Men from Virginia Union (Box-folder 70:35)
    - The New York Contingent (Box-folder 70:36)
    - N.T. in Tent (Glory of Noels) (Box-folder 70:37)
    - Unidentified Soldiers and Tents (Box-folder 70:38)
    - Postcards from Ames Iowa (Box-folder 70:39)
    - Entrance to Fort Ames- Iowa (Box-folder 70:40)
    - Out on the reservations (Box-folder 70:41)
    - The Barracks (Box-folder 70:42)
  - Photographs- Friends (by name) or school affiliations
    - Allen, Robert (Box-folder 71:1)
    - Alphonso and Flossie (Box-folder 71:2)
    - Atkins (Box-folder 71:3)
    - Auter Henry (Box-folder 71:4)
    - Bertha (Box-folder 71:5)
    - Blackwell, James H. (Box-folder 71:6)
    - Bland, Pompey (Box-folder 71:7)
    - Belling, Boyton and Branch (Box-folder 71:8)
    - The Branson Children (Box-folder 71:9)
    - The Branson Children (Box-folder 71:10)
    - The Branson Children (Box-folder 71:11)
    - The Branson Children (Box-folder 71:12)
    - Quien Brown (Box-folder 71:13)
    - Bryne Street (Box-folder 71:14)
    - Anna Carter (Box-folder 71:15)
    - J.M. Carter (Box-folder 71:16)
    - Sante Chambliss (Box-folder 71:17)
    - LuLu Chare (Box-folder 71:18)
    - Marguerite Chew (Box-folder 71:19)
    - Julia Claibourne (s.n 1915) (Box-folder 71:20)
    - D.A Clifford (Box-folder 71:21)
    - Eva Holmes Coles (Box-folder 71:22)
    - M.M. Contee (Box-folder 71:23)
    - Annie Crittender (Box-folder 71:24)
    - A.M.C Daniel (Box-folder 71:25)
    - Bobby Davenport and mother (Box-folder 71:26)
    - W.E.B DuBios (Box-folder 71:27)
    - L.H. Foster (Box-folder 71:28)
    - John M. Gandy Jr. (10 Photo's) (Box-folder 71:29)
      - John M. Gandy Jr. (with mother)
      - Back of Storum
      - With Edna Colson
      - With Edna Colson, Felicia Ardera, Bea Watson, Anna Laura Lindsay, Johnella Frazer Jackson and W. Hamlin
    - The Gerrsids (Box-folder 71:30)
    - Charles Gilpin (Box-folder 71:31)
    - George Green (Box-folder 71:32)
    - Elizabeth Garland Hall (Box-folder 71:33)
    - George Hall (Lieut) YMCA (Box-folder 71:34)
    - Ida (Morris) Harris (Box-folder 71:35)
    - Martin A. Harris (school teacher, South Richmond) (Box-folder 71:36)
    - Octavia Harris (from P.George)
    - Helda Harris (Box-folder 71:38)
    - Williams W. Hill (Box-folder 71:39)
    - Mathelda Honnay (YMCA Belgium) (Box-folder 71:40)
    - Henry Martin Holmes (Box-folder 71:41)
    - William F. Jackson and others (Box-folder 71:42)
    - William Henry Johnson (Box-folder 71:43)
    - Susie Matthews Johnson 71:44 (Box-folder 71:44)
    - Virgil Johnson (Box-folder 71:45)
    - Mary Jones (Box-folder 71:46)
    - Wesley Jones (Danville-Baremhigs-Ris) (Box-folder 71:47)
    - Frederick Kersey and Amaza Meredith (Box-folder 71:48)
    - Alice Kersey (Box-folder 71:49)
    - Leona Kersey (Box-folder 71:50)